A Guide to the Papers of Walt Whitman, 1838-1987
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series 1: Literary Manuscripts
  - "The Soul's Procession," [ca. 1869], AMsS, 13 leaves (3 pp. loosely inserted) with attached news clipping, "The Steamship Pereire Disaster," January 28 [1869], and partial typed excerpts from manuscript. #5604. (Box-folder 1:93)
    - Page 6. The Soul's Procession, ca. 1869, 1 leaf, handwritten, 20.5 x 12.5 cm.
      On the first page (20.5 x 12.5 cm.) of the type B gathering, which starts after the type A page following leaf 6. The page is blank below the title, which is inscribed and underlined in pencil.
    - Page 7. The general idea-passing, ca. 1869, 1 leaf, handwritten, 20.5 x 12.5 cm.
      On the second page of the type B gathering (Whitman did not use the versos). Inscribed and revised in (smudged) pencil. The note "Agassiz—/ Animal Life p. 53" at the center of the page apparently refers to Louis Agassiz' The Structure of Animal Life, delivered as six lectures in 1862 and first published in 1865. A horizontal line separates the upper set of notes from lower ones, which are formatted as trial verses.
    - Page 8. The material is all, ca. 1869, 1 leaf, handwritten, 20.5 x 12.5 cm.
      On the third page of the type B gathering. The first half of the page is devoted to pencil trial verses that represent a continuation of Leaf 8. Following these, and separated from them by a horizontal line in black ink, occurs a set of prose notes beginning with the words "Make a succession/ of splendid gorgeous/ stately pageants or/ moving panoramas."
    - Page 9. The successive developments, ca. 1869, 1 leaf, handwritten, 20.5 x 12.5 cm.
      On the fourth page of the type B gathering. Inscribed in (somewhat smudged) black ink. These notes represent an intermediate stage between prose notes and trial verses; they are formatted as verses, but contain Whitman's instructions to himself, offering an outline of future verses rather than a sketch.
    - Page 10. All these shows are for, ca. 1869, 1 leaf, handwritten, 20.5 x 12.5 cm.
      On the sixth page of the type B gathering. Inscribed and revised in black ink. Whitman's note "Query?" appears above the first line. Several phrases, like "History," "The Wars," and "The greatest philosophers," are inscribed in very large letters and underlined.
    - Page 12. Then at the end, ca. 1869, 1 leaf, handwritten, 19.5 x 12.5 cm.
      On the first type A page after the type B gathering. These highly fragmentary prose and verse notes are inscribed in pencil and blue crayon, with some revisions to the blue crayon section in the same medium. Different sections of the notes are separated with dashes.
    - Page 13. Piece on Greenwood Cemetery, ca. 1869, 1 leaf, handwritten, 19.5 x 12.5 cm.
      On the second type A page after the type B gathering. Inscribed, quite shakily, in pencil. The working title is underlined. As indicated above, these lines represent an intermediate stage between prose notes and trial verses. The different sections are separated by short horizontal lines. Although Whitman wrote about Greenwood Cemetery (Brooklyn) elsewhere, he did not use these notes for the independent poem he was apparently projecting on this leaf.
  - "Sounds of the Winter" under "Old Age Echoes." (Box-folder 1:94)
    The general title appears to be Old Age Echoes, but beneath that title are the two poems under which titles the item is catalogued: Sounds of the Winter and The Unexpress'd. Pasted to the leaf below the second poem is a woodcut engraving of Walt Whitman along with his autograph. Under that is what has been classified as two lines from an unidentified poem. A note at top states, "intended to make one page."
  - "Spenser's single objects...," n.d., AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:1)
    From "Shorter Notes, Isolated Words" section #54.
  - "Studies of Womanhood," [ca. 1850-1860], AMs, 5 pp. on 5 l., mounted, #3829 (Bowers #21). (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Fragment 1. Poem of Names, 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 7.5 cm. x 12.5 cm.
      Pencil on white paper. Pasted on top half of archival leaf.
    - Fragment 2. ?Poem of different incidents, 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 12 cm. x 13 cm.
      Ink on pink paper. Pasted on bottom half of archival leaf.
    - Fragment 3. Mothers precede all, 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 8 cm. x 13.5 cm.
      Pencil on verso of envelope. Pasted on top half of archival leaf.
    - Fragment 4. In Poems, 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 7.5 cm. x 15.5 cm.
      Ink on blue paper. Pasted on bottom half of archival leaf. Verso has some notes for poem [America, so young and so magnificent].
    - Fragment 5. Intersperse here and, 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 5.5 cm. x 8 cm.
      Written in ink. Pasted on top third of archival leaf.
    - Fragment 6. Poem of Kisses, 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 5 cm. x 9.5 cm.
      Written in ink. Pasted in middle of archival leaf.
    - Fragment 7. Song in Poem of Kisses, 1850-1880, 1 leaf, handwritten, 7.5 cm. x 11.5 cm.
      Written in pencil. Pasted on bottom third of archival leaf.
    - Fragment 8. Poem illustrative of the Woman under the 'new dispensation', 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 17 cm. x 16 cm.
      Written in ink. Pasted to own archival leaf.
    - Fragment 9. You woman, mother of children, 1850-1860, 1 leaf, handwritten, 24.5 cm. x 24.5 cm.
      Ink on lined paper. Pasted on own archival leaf.
  - "Sustenance for the great geniuses...," n.d., AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:3)
    From "Memoranda from Books" section #64.
  - "They do not seem to me...," [ca. 1860], AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., handwritten, 13 cm. x 11.5 cm., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:4)
    This manuscript is a draft of lines that were published in Chants Democratic, number 13, in the 1860 edition of Leaves of Grass. That poem was later revised and published as Laws for Creations; however, the lines on this manuscript are a draft of the section of the poem that was deleted after the 1860 publication.
  - "A Thought of Columbus," [ca. 1891], AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., handwritten, 12.5 cm. x 25 cm., Barrow, #3829 (Bowers #8). (Box-folder 2:5)
    A draft of A Thought of Columbus, a poem first published on July 16, 1892, in Once a Week, accompanied by Horace Traubel's account of its composition, called "Walt Whitman's Last Poem." This manuscript is a draft of only the first six lines and is dated 1891.
  - "Three verses-One for North, One for South, One for West," n.d., AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., handwritten, 22.5 x 13.5 cm., Barrow, #3829 (Bowers #27). (Box-folder 2:6)
    On one leaf of white wove paper (22.5 x 13.5 cm.), in very dark brown-black ink, with revisions in the same ink and in pencil. Multiple pinholes just below center. At the top, which is damaged, can be seen a title or notes for a different poem reading [One?] Song—Come Philander; the preliminary and incomplete draft of Three verses (with the note "2d or 3d verse" and a question mark at different points) appears beneath a horizontal line. Whitman apparently never revised the poem further, and it was never published. At some point the leaf was folded in half, apparently to form part of a small notebook. On the verso appear two independent texts. One is a list of names and addresses (beginning with his brother and sisters "Jeff./ Mary/ Han[nah]" and including his friends and supporters Mrs. [Anne Burrows] Gilchrist, W[illiam] M[ichael] Rossetti, and [Edward] Dowden) of people to whom Whitman had apparently mailed copies of an article or book; all but two of the names are checked off in ink or in orange crayon. On the facing half-leaf, in pencil (mostly erased or deleted) and struck through with the same orange crayon, appear what seem to be notes for a newspaper announcement, beginning "Walt Whitman, after an absence of almost three years, appeared again on Pennsylvania Avenue this forenoon." Based on this date it can be speculated that the notes were written late in 1875 (a possibility corroborated by the list of names), but the poem(s) may have been inscribed in the late 1860s or earlier.
  - "Time, always without break...," 1887 March 14, AMsS, 1 leaf, handwritten, 27 cm. x 20.5 cm., #3839-j. (Box-folder 2:7)
    This manuscript is a quotation from Song of the Answerer (from section two, two lines beginning "Time always without break") and Whitman's signature. The manuscript is dated March 14, 1887.
  - "The Time and Lands are devoted to the Real," [ca. 1872], AMs, 2 pp. on 2 l., handwritten, 18.5 x 18.5 cm. to 20 x 18 cm., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:8)
    On two sections of white, gray-ruled laid Department of Justice letterhead, the first cut down to 20 x 18 cm. and the second reduced to 18.5 x 18.5 cm. The engraved heading is missing from the first leaf but appears on the verso of the second, above the date "187[ ]." Both pages are inscribed in black ink, with revisions in the same and in brown-black ink. The first two entries on Leaf 1 appear to contain general notes for this poem; the second entry reads, "Make a demand for/ the Ideal, (or/ rather idea of the/ Ideal of the real)." This is followed by the note "in the piece," which leads up to several trial verses eventually incorporated in the second verse paragraph of numbered section 5 of Thou Mother With Thy Equal Brood. Leaf 2 ("? Or—a song—a chant/ which shall sing—celebrate/—America..."): these general notes, ending with a cartoon hand singling out the lines "All the states/ East & west,/ north & south/ Brotherhood/ an equal union[,]" prefigure the whole poem, but particularly such lines as "South, North, West, East,/ (To thy immortal breasts, Mother of All, thy every daughter,/ son, endear'd alike, forever equal,)" in the same section projected on Leaf 1.
  - "A tip-top caricature of Walt Whitman," [ca. 1872], AMs, 1 leaf, handwritten, 15.5 cm. x 20.5 cm., #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:9)
    This manuscript is a draft of a piece for a periodical advertising the presence of a new "burlesque portrait" of Whitman by Frank Bellew. It was apparently published in the Fifth Avenue Journal in 1872.
  - "To a Literat," [1857-1859], AMs, 1 leaf, handwritten, 21 cm. x 12 cm., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:10)
    On a tax form trimmed down to 21 x 12 cm., with the upper corners cropped diagonally. Two sets of pinholes. The first two verses, taken more or less directly from [Of Biography], have no revisions, but the remaining three verses represent a significant expansion of the themes in the prose notes and are extensively revised. Two of the corrections are in brown ink. These verses, which precede [Walt Whitman's law] in the composition process, correspond, like [Of Biography], to section 2 of the 1860 version of the poem.
  - "To an Exclusive," n.d., AMs, 2 pp. on 2 l., 20.5 cm. x 13 cm., with typed transcription. #3829 (Bowers #5). (Box-folder 2:11)
    Two leaves of ink on pink paper. Verso of second leaf is ordered list of poems beginning with "33 A Handful of Air" and ending with "72 Leaf." Note indicates poem as unpublished.
  - "Today," [ca. 1888], AMs, 1 leaf, handwritten, 20 x 25 cm., #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:12)
    Note on top states "sent April 21 to Herald."
  - "Trent Affair," n.d., AN, 1 leaf, handwritten, 14 cm. x 15.5 cm., #3829 (Bowers #68). (Box-folder 2:13)
    On the top half of leaf is a printed, struck-through copy of the note about the Trent Affair which accompanied Whitman's poem For Queen Victoria's Birthday, which was published first in 1890. On the bottom half of leaf is a note written in purple pencil reading, "W.W.'s respects—/—if convenient print in paper of 24th/—no pay expected."
  - "Two Rivulets," [ca. 1875], AMs, 1 leaf, handwritten, 22.5 cm. x 16.5 cm., Barrow. #3829 (Bowers #6). (Box-folder 2:14)
    A partial draft of the Preface to Two Rivulets, a volume published in 1876.
  - "The Unexpressed" under "Old Age Echoes." (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Unidentified Manuscript, ca. 1880, AMs fragment, 1 p. on 1 l., Barrow, #3829-y. (Box-folder 2:16)
    Possibly Democratic Vistas.
  - "The Wall about Martyrs," [1888], AMsS, 3 fragments attached on 1 leaf, handwritten, 11.5 cm. x 20.5 cm., Barrow, #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:17)
    Note at bottom states "sent to Herald March 11." Written in ink and partially on verso of letter addressed to Walt Whitman from London.
  - "Walt Whitman: A description of His Birthplace...," 1850 September 11, 12, 13, AMs, 2 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:18)
    Includes copy of drawing, "Where Walt Whitman was Born"; printed sheet, "Walt Whitman, His Home and His Inspiring Oak"; typed description of Whitman's birthplace.
  - "Walt Whitman is putting the later touches...," [1890 November 10], AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:19)
    Autobiographical sketch for publication in "The Critic."
  - "Walt Whitman's law...," [ca. 1857-1859], AMs, 1 leaf, handwritten, 22 cm. x 12 cm., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:20)
    On a full tax form (22 cm. x 12 cm.) with the corners slightly cropped diagonally. Two sets of pinholes in center. This leaf, bearing the deleted title To an artist, literat, &c and first line "Come, I have now to tell/ you[,]" revises and expands on To a Literat.— It was revised to form sections 1 and 2 of the 1860 version of the poem, after first being revised itself in the leaves described under Chants Democratic below.
  - "Walt Whitman's Works, 1876 Edition," [ca. 1876], Autograph revisions to book review, initialed, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:21)
  - "We suppose it will excite the mirth...," n.d., AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:22)
    From "Notes on the Meaning and Intention of 'Leaves of Grass,'" section #59.
  - "the whale-boat, 'the harpoonersman,'" [late 1850's], AMs, 1 leaf, handwritten, 21 cm. x 12 cm., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:23)
    This manuscript contains notes about whales. The relationship of this manuscript to Whitman's published work is unknown. These notes may be a continuation of notes written on a separate leaf and held at Duke University (The Trent Collection of Walt Whitman Manuscripts, Duke University Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library), "The Whale," MS 4 to 88.
  - "Whitman's Poems summed up, [ca. 1876], AMs, 4 pp. on 4 l., with typed transcription, #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:24)
  - "With every heaving wave," [ca. 1880's], AMs fragment, 1 leaf, handwritten, 24 cm. x 14.5 cm., #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:25)
    Believed to be for or from some poem in Sands at Seventy. Final version of poem entitled, "By That Long Scan of Waves." Written in purple pencil and ink. Includes a negative photostat of manuscript.
  - "You Tides with Ceaseless Swell," [ca. 1888-1889], AMs, 1 p. on 1 l., 25 cm. x 19.5 cm., with typed transcription. #3829 (Bowers #24). (Box-folder 2:26)
    One leaf in ink on lined paper with pencil revisions.
- Series II: Miscellaneous Manuscripts
  - Mortgage signed by Walter Whitman and Louisa Whitman, 1838 January 9-February 8, DS, 3 pp. on 4 l., Barrow, #3829-q. (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Pocket Notebook, 1863, AMs, 17 pp., 8 leaves, handwritten, 12 cm. x 20 cm., #3829. (Box-folder 2:28)
    Pocket notebook of Walt Whitman in which he made notes of his visits with patients in Civil War hospitals. Consists of notes written in pencil on 8 leaves of paper folded in half to form a booklet which is bound with a pink ribbon. The notebook lists names and details about various Civil War soldiers that Whitman met while volunteering in Washington, D. C., hospitals during the war.
  - Walt Whitman's Will, 1873 May 15-16, ADS, 3 pp. on 1 l., measuring 34 cm. x 21 cm., written in ink on legal foolscap (lined paper), with a typed description, #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Walt Whitman to the U.S. Department of Justice, 1874 December 2, ADS fragment, 2 pp. on 1 l., #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:30)
  - Printed Map of the United States of America, [1879], D, 1 p. on 1 l., silking, #3829 (Bowers #67). (Box-folder 2:31)
    With autograph lines by Walt Whitman showing his past and proposed trips.
  - Autograph signature, 1881 October 18, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-j. (Box-folder 2:32)
  - [Walt Whitman] to J. W. Bartlett, [1884 July 6], Autographed envelope with enclosure and explanatory note by J. W. Bartlett on back of envelope, 1 item. #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:33)
  - Flower and pin with signed inscription, "From Walt Whitman's breast 'posy,'" 1886 January 6, Artifact, in sealed mylar envelope, 1 item. #10204-az. (Box-folder 2:34)
  - United States 49th Congress, 2nd Session, 1886-1887, House of Representatives, Report No. 3856 on "Walt Whitman," 1887 February 1, D, 3 pp. on 2 l., Barrow, #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:35)
  - [Walt Whitman] to Talcott Williams, [1890 December 6], Autographed envelope, 1 item, #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Walt Whitman's last will and testament, 1891 December 24, DS, 4 pp. on 2 l., in hand of Thomas B. [Harned], lawyer and literary executor to Whitman, #5604. (Box-folder 2:37)
  - Legal Document establishing Louisa Orr Whitman as Walt Whitman's executor, 1892 April 7, DS, 1 p. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:38)
  - Legal Document establishing Louisa Orr Whitman as Walt Whitman's executor, 1892 April 8, DS, 1 p. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:39)
  - Certification of Augusta Harned and Elizabeth Keller attesting to authenticity of the codicil to Walt Whitman's will, 1892 April 8, DS, 1 p. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:40)
  - [Walt Whitman] to Melville Phillips, n.d., Autographed envelope, 1 item, #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:41)
  - [Walt Whitman] to Dion Thomas, n.y. October 16, Autographed envelope, 1 item, #3829 (Bowers #39). (Box-folder 2:42)
  - Self-addressed envelope, n.y. March 17, 1 item, #3829-j. (Box-folder 2:43)
  - [Walt Whitman] to [Tal]cott Williams, n.d., Autographed envelope, 1 item, #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:44)
- Series III: Correspondence
  - Ellen C. Ahern to R. V. Thornton, 1949 July 21, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:45)
    Regarding Whitman correspondence to Robert Underwood Johnson, 1879 October 29.
  - H. M. Alden to Walt Whitman, 1873 November 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #3829 (Bowers #32). (Box-folder 2:46)
  - Jack Biriss to Carroll Atwood Wilson, 1936 February 25, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #3829-z. (Box-folder 2:47)
  - Richard [Maurice] Bucke to Walt [Whitman], 1886 June 9, 4 pp. on 1 l., with envelope, #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:48)
  - John Burroughs to [John Jay] Knox, 1873 September 14, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l., with envelope, #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:49)
  - John Burroughs to [Clara Barrus], [1906] November 19, ALS, 12 pp. on 12 l., #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:50)
  - Edward Carpenter to Walt [Whitman], 1878 May 13, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:51)
  - E[dward] Clifford to [E. R.] Pease, [1885 June 24], ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:52)
    Edward Clifford is an English artist.
  - Mary Davis to Dr. [Raley] Bell, 1903 May 13, ALS, 3p. on 3 l., with envelope, Barrow, #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:53)
  - Mary Davis to Dr. [Raley] Bell, 1903 December 23, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:54)
  - Mary Davis to Dr. [Raley] Bell, 1906 August 21, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-a. (Box-folder 2:55)
  - Peter Doyle to Walt [Whitman], [1868?] September 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #3829 (Bowers #33). (Box-folder 2:56)
  - Peter [Doyle] to Walt [Whitman], [1868] September 23, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:57)
  - Peter [Doyle] to Walt [Whitman], [1868] October 1, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l., #3829-h. (Box-folder 2:58)
  - Pete[r] [Doyle] to Walt [Whitman], n.y. October 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #3829 (Bowers #36). (Box-folder 2:59)
  - Charley [Eldridge] to Walt [Whitman], 1873 October 15, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:60)
  - Ralph Waldo Emerson to Walt Whitman, 1855 July 21, Xerox copy of facsimile, 7 pp. on 7 l., #3829-o. (Box-folder 2:61)
  - Charles E. Feinberg to Francis L. Berkeley, Jr. 1958 May 8, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:62)
    Regarding a Walt Whitman letter to Peter Doyle, 1888 November 19, proven to be a forgery.
  - H[orace] Howard Furness to [Edmund] Gosse, 1892 March 29, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:63)
  - Ann Gilchrist to Walt Whitman, 1879 October 6, ALS, 8 pp. on 2 l., with typed transcription. #3829 (Bowers #34). (Box-folder 2:64)
    Originally enclosed in Walt Whitman letter to John Burroughs, [1879] November 23.
  - Ann Gilchrist to Edward Pease, 1885 January 24, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:65)
  - Ann Gilchrist to [Edward] Pease, 1885 June 28, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:66)
  - Ann Gilchrist to [Edward] Pease, 1885 July 1, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:67)
  - Ann Gilchrist to [Edward] Pease, 1885 July 3, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:68)
  - Ann Gilchrist to [Edward] Pease, 1885 July 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:69)
  - Ann Gilchrist to [Edward] Pease, [1885?] July 14, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:70)
  - Ann Gilchrist to [Edward] Pease, [1885?] July 20, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:71)
  - J. B. Gilder to [Walt] Whitman, 1887 March 17, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. regarding Tennyson-Whitman correspondence, #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:72)
    SEE verso Walt Whitman to [J. B. Gilder], [1887] March 18.
  - J. L. and J. B. Gilder to [Walt Whitman], 1890 November 1, TLS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:73)
    SEE verso of AMs, "Walt Whitman is putting the later touches...."
  - Joseph Jackson to Mr. Borneman, 1943 July 28, TLS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:74)
    Regarding a pencil sketch by Joseph Jackson completed at Walt Whitman's birthday dinner in Philadelphia on May 31, 1890.
  - [?] Johnston to [Walt Whitman], 1874 July 16, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:75)
    See verso of manuscript fragment, "the best part of literature and religion."
  - J. Johnston to James W. Watt, 1901 March 25, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., #3829-l. (Box-folder 2:76)
  - J[ohn] H. Johnston to Mr. Watson, 1912 March 11, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:77)
    Includes Whitman manuscript, "the city as well as country. Other wars..." and photograph of Walt Whitman, Harry, and Kitty Johnston.
  - Jacob Klein to W. S. Kennedy, 1881 September 1, ALS photocopy, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope, #3829-j. (Box-folder 2:78)
  - W. J. Linton to [Walt Whitman], n.d., ALS fragment, 1 p. on 1 l. on verso of leaf 11, Song of the Redwood Tree, 2nd draft. (Box-folder 2:78-a)
  - Edwin Miller to R. V. Thornton, 1957 December 24, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-i. (Box-folder 2:79)
    Regarding Whitman correspondence to C. F. Currie, 1890 August 1.
  - Edwin Miller to C. Waller Barrett, 1960 November 4, TLS, 1 p on 1 l., #3829-j. (Box-folder 2:80)
    Regarding Whitman correspondence to Oran S. Baldwin, 1883 December 15.
  - Edwin Miller to C. Waller Barrett, 1960 December 24, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., #3829-j. (Box-folder 2:81)
  - Thomas Hancock [Nunn?] to E. R. Pease, 1885 June 24, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:82)
  - Albert B. [Otis] to [Walt Whitman], 1873 September 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; photocopy. (Box-folder 2:83)
  - James Parton to [?], 1867 November 26, ANS, 1 p. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:84)
    Regarding Walt Whitman's financial state, with attached clipping from Boston Saturday Evening Gazette, November 17, 1867.
  - Abby H. Price to Mrs. George Whitman, n.y. October [17?], ALS, on verso of page in Song of the Redwood Trees. (Box-folder 2:85)
  - Ernest Rhys to Walt Whitman, 1887 March 29, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l., #3829 (Bowers #35). (Box-folder 2:86)
    SEE Walt Whitman to [William Sloane Kennedy?], ALS, April 11, 1887.
  - T. W. Rolleston to Walt Whitman, 1888 September 1, APCS, 1 p., #3829 (Bowers #64). (Box-folder 2:87)
  - J.H. Rome to James W. Watt, 1900 August 4, ALS with envelope, #3829-l. (Box-folder 2:88)
  - [Charles Rowley, Jr.] to E. R. Pease, 1885 June 26, AN, 1 p. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:89)
  - Charles Rowley, Jr. to E. R. Pease, 1885 June 29, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., #5604. (Box-folder 2:90)